[Music]
welcome to this business Central launch
event about what's new in Al go for
GitHub on delivery and deployment my
name is Freddy Christensen I'm a
technical evangelist with Microsoft in
Copenhagen and together with me I have
my name is Sebastian and I'm a software
engineer at Microsoft and I recently
joined the team late December last year
we are happy for that so the first thing
we're going to talk about is dependency
install mode which actually is a
requirement that came to us from a
partner he actually created a PR on algo
and said he would like functionality
like this and we digged into that and
found out there was a better way to do
that but now the feature is there and it
determines or it's a it's a setting that
you set on an environment that
determines how dependencies are handled
at deploy time uh originally
if you were trying to deploy an app and
the dependencies were not there uh not
included then uh the app would like fail
installation uh what we do now is we try
to install the dependency from uh from
appsource if if you've decided that you
want dependencies either upgraded or
installed um let's have a quick look at
a video now looking at this report
we have like this run where we have a
multiproject repo and a deploy mode over
here to uh the
BCL environment here and we can see that
that we have one app to deploy that's
version 1.24 here and some dependencies
that are uh from an older version so
dependencies to upgrade the upgrade here
comes from the dependency install mode
set to upgrade meaning that if these
apps are installed in a prior version
they'll be upgraded to the latest
version I don't have any dependencies on
appsource apps here but if I had they
will also be installed and handled in
the same way so if there were any
updates to that they will be included in
that one um as we can see here these
were already installed in the same
version meaning that the deployment is
is very fast and the reason for this is
that we are using incremental bills to
to this one let's have a look at how the
setting looks it is in
our GitHub algo settings file under
deploy to ble we'll have the dependency
install mode set to upgrade with that
next topic is about including test apps
during
deployment we have two features we want
to support number one is deploying test
apps uh and number two is automatically
running tests for this presentation we
have implemented the first
version um and all you have to do is
prepare your online environment which
should be a Sandbox
environment and then enable this feature
in Alo
settings this is under the deploy to
structure which you have used many times
before uh for your deployments to
environments on top of that uh we now
also have the option to exclude
apps by ID when you deploy so in case
you want to test only a specific app you
can out do
that uh and let's run a demo showing how
this works here I have a symbol
repository uh a single project
repository with two apps uh and two test
apps what I want to do is deploy app one
alongside the two test apps so app one
app one. test and app one. performance
test I want to exclude app
2 in my repository settings in GitHub
Alo settings. Json and I'll
Define two new things in my deploy to
structure I Define include test apps in
sandbox environment as
true and exclude app IDs which is an
array and in here I put the ID of app
2 now when I run my uh publish to
environment this will automatically
deploy the test apps and exclude uh app
2 to show how this looks I will go to my
environment and here I have my list of
extensions we'll see here that app1 was
deployed and app one. test was deployed
however the performance test app was not
deployed well that is intentional the
performance test app depends on a test
Library which is not available as an
appsource app and that automatically
gets picked up during deployment and
excluded so if you depend on something
that is start in appsource gallery it
will not be included this also works if
you have a custom deployment
script if this setting is enabled then
all your test apps will be passed to
your deployment script and you simply
have to handle dependency installation
on your
own in this next topic I want to show
you how we can deploy artifacts from a
pool request uh and this was a request
from a partner
we now have a new option for deploying
pool request changes directly to an
online environment this is useful for
quick testing uh in case you need to
test in your online environment uh
before you complete your PR with a code
review and merge it into your main
branch for now this is a manual process
where you will use the published to
environment
workflow give it a pool request ID
instead of a version and then click run
work flow later on we want to
investigate how we can do this
automatically in such a way that every
time you push a new change to a PR then
those changes will automatically flow
into your online
environment as you can see in the little
box to your right all you have to do is
give it a poest ID um written as prore
ID and I want to demo this so here I
have a Syle PR with symbol change in the
address bar I can see that this uh PR or
here I can see that it has uh ID
28 so what I do is I go
to um oh sorry here to publish to
environment I run the
workflow instead of selecting current or
latest like you might normally do I
simply say
prore
28 I select my test environment which I
want to deploy to and then I click run
workflow and that will now deploy
changes from that
PR um I have a PR build ready here for
that
PR um and you can see here it points to
last no good build well that is because
if incremental bills is enabled then in
order to save space uh and storage we
will only
publish artifacts built in or apps built
built in this specific PR what the
deployment will do is it will grab the
remaining apps which were not built
inside this PR from the last known good
build and deploy those as well and this
is done to save storage for you which is
costly if you have um a private
repository normally pull request uh
artifacts are only valid for one day so
you might run into an issue where you
run your publish to environment using a
PR where you get an error saying that
your artifacts have expired this is
normal uh artifacts will expire after
one day using normal settings and we
encourage you to keep settings this way
if your artifacts have expired all you
have to do is Rerun the P request build
and when that is done you can run your
published to environment again thanks
for watching this video and see you
again next
time thank you